# PRATEEK WADHWA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER +447879975651

## • DETAILS •

+447879975651 w1234panku@gmail.com

o LINKS o

Prateek Wadhwa

o SKILLS o

React

Linux

MySQL

Git C++

Advanced Analytical Thinking Skills

SQL

Python

Java

**Amazon Web Services** 

Angular

**Machine Learning** 

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Punjabi

## PROFILE

Software Engineer

Highly professional, capable, ambitious with more than 2 years of experience in Development. Work to extremely high and exacting standards in demanding and fast-paced testing environments with precision, accuracy, and meticulous attention to detail; always delivering efficient and effective end-to-end solutions for the client. Attempt to be fully up to date with new technologies continuously coming on stream at a frequent rate.

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Software Engineer at Hsbc Software Development India, Pune

June 2019 — August 2021

- Developed and automated web applications for internal clients in Java.
- Established a new structure of data transfer in HSBC securities and services
  Developed end-to-end application in python flask.
- It enabled effective communication between architects and the project teams.
- Developed web application in angular and react on front-end and java spring-boot in back-end for MRD (Master reference data).

#### Software Engineer at EME Technologies, Mohali

January 2019 — June 2019

 Developed full-stack web application that can automate document submissions in schools and colleges digitally.

#### Software Solutions Architect at Holovis, England

December 2021 — Present

- Write Unit test cases for server-side python code.
- Create AWS Lambdas written in python.
- Write Unit and integration tests for server-side python code.
- Refactor SAM template in AWS cloud formation.
- Diagnose and fix bugs throughout our AWS stack.
- To develop, write and document code to professional standards of architectural integrity and robust performance.

# EDUCATION

#### 10th Standard, Chandigarh

March 2011 — March 2013

Grade: 10 CGPA out of 10

## 12th standard, Chandigarh

March 2013 — March 2015

Grade: 87.6 out of 100

BTech in Computer Science, Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology, Punjab

August 2015 — June 2019

7.64 CGPA out of 10

Masters in Computing science, University of Glasgow, New Glasgow

September 2021 — September 2022

# Still pursuing



# Achievements

- Chess: Internationally FIDE-rated chess player Participated in Chess School nationals in 2011,2012 Participated in inter Engineering and all India inter-university chess events.
- Maths: Participated in RMO Olympiad and secured top 5 ranks in 2011,2012.
- Pat on the back: Got rewarded Pat on the back award in HSBC technology India for my contribution in Q-1 2020.